<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</title>
    <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aaassembly.org/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Windy Chien</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/windy-chien/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/windy-chien/</guid>
      <description>Algorithms, Aesthetics, and the Artist’s Hand
If an algorithm is a set of rules that defines a sequence of operations, what does that look like in the hand of a visual artist? Windy Chien speaks about her work with rope and teaches how to tie a knot.
Windy Chien makes art that activates space and elevates the vernacular. She is best known for her 2016 work, The Year of Knots, in which she learned a new knot every day for a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Wilson</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/elizabeth-wilson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/elizabeth-wilson/</guid>
      <description>Algorithms, music and machines
Algorithms are becoming ubiquitous in society and personal data is being used to drive their decisions. The rise of AI-powered interfaces has seen more devices present in everyday life, such as Google and Amazon’s conversational interfaces, whose algorithms are becoming more obfuscated. There is a need for a shift in focus to repurpose devices and their algorithms as creative tools and for exposed processes in doing so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia Jack</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/olivia-jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/olivia-jack/</guid>
      <description>Hydra, Live Coding Visuals in the Browser
Olivia Jack talks about her Hydra project which invites you to reimagine pixels and color, melt your screen live into glitches and textures, and do it all for free on the Web – as you play with others.
Olivia Jack is a programmer and artist who works frequently with open-source software, cartography, live coding, and experimental interfaces. Her research interests include algorithmic representations of uncertainty and chaos, peer2peer networking, and live coding as a way to enter into a continuous dialogue or feedback loop between herself and her computer, among other things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yotam Mann &amp; Sarah Rothberg</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/yotam-mann-sarah-rothberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/yotam-mann-sarah-rothberg/</guid>
      <description>Blobchat, a Typed-Talk
Yotam and Sarah communicate about communication, using a text-based musical communication interface. The interface is part of their ongoing project, Blobchat, which combines sound, machine-learning, gesture, and chatrooms as a way to ask: is misunderstanding a part of understanding? How do machines mediate? How else can they?
Sarah Rothberg is an artist who captures the interplay between technology, systems, and the personal, creating meaning through unique and strange interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chelley Sherman &amp; Christopher Latina</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/chelleysherman-christopherlatina/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/chelleysherman-christopherlatina/</guid>
      <description>Perceptual Geometries
Chelley Sherman is an interactive media artist creating XR audio visual works. Christopher Latina is an engineer, composer and designer working with hybrid hardware and software mediums to create immersive environments. Chelley will explain her evolution of designing &amp;ldquo;Dispersion&amp;rdquo;, an immersive VR experience and other sonic environment into organic 3D spatial sound sculptures and explore different modes of sensory and perceptual illusion using spatial audio, haptics, and virtual and augmented reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jules Litman-Cleper</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jules-litman-cleper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jules-litman-cleper/</guid>
      <description>Queering Generativity, Querying Generativity: Generative Algorithms and Postnatural narratives
This talk will focus on Generative algorithms, growth algorithms, Evolutionary and Life simulation in order to ask how algorithmic principles, and their rendered visual outputs, construct and deconstruct narratives about the &amp;ldquo;natural&amp;rdquo; the &amp;ldquo;living&amp;rdquo;&amp;quot; and &amp;ldquo;non-living&amp;rdquo; and the dynamics of gendered social relations.
Jules Litman-Cleper is interested in simulated space and materiality as a new creative substrate, with the potential to generate knowledge about our patterns of interaction with information and environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jon Leidecker</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jon-leidecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jon-leidecker/</guid>
      <description>United Feedback
The seemingly recent interests in generative music and creative machine learning in fact stem back to the earliest electronic music studio in the United States, run by Louis and Bebe Barron. Their statements of purpose, encompassing cybernetics and self-playing circuits, place feedback as the defining idiomatic voice of the medium, and the central organizing principle of a live performance method. This lecture traces commonalities in the works of the Barrons, Ussachevsky, David Tudor, the members of the Sonic Arts Union, Eliane Radigue and Roland Kayn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Roberts</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-roberts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-roberts/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Creative Potential of Deep Learning through the Magenta Project
Over the past 3 years, the increase in the generative power of deep neural networks has been staggering. WaveNets can produce speech nearly indistinguishable from humans, GANs generate images of imagined faces in great detail, and Music Transformers can play piano like a virtuoso. In this talk we will examine the recent progress in deep learning-based generative models and see how this new technology can be used as a tool to enhance, not replace human creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marc Weidenbaum</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/marc-weidenbaum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/marc-weidenbaum/</guid>
      <description>The Woodshed Is a Black Box
How a rules-based system formed, shapes, and fuels the long-running online music community known as the Disquiet Junto.
Marc Weidenbaum founded the website Disquiet.com in 1996 at the intersection of sound, art, and technology, and since 2012 has moderated the Disquiet Junto, an active online community of weekly music/sonic projects that explore creative constraints. A former editor of Tower Records&#39; music magazines, Weidenbaum is the author of the 33 1/3 book on Aphex Twin’s classic album Selected Ambient Works Volume II, and has written for Nature, Boing Boing, Pitchfork, Downbeat, NewMusicBox, Art Practical, The Atlantic online, and numerous other periodicals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Florin</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-florin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-florin/</guid>
      <description>The Formalist-Industrial Complex
Brian Eno, who coined the phrase “generative music”, recently likened it to gardening—but the material practice is just as much rooted in centuries of formal aesthetics, predictive statistics, and industrial automation. How can we negotiate the tension between the organic and the mechanical in the algorithmic arts?
Adam Florin is an independent UX Engineer, who has been creating interactive media for 10+ years for clients such as Levi&amp;rsquo;s®, Facebook, MoMA, General Electric, and Google, earning a South by Southwest Interactive award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPACEFILLER</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/spacefiller/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/spacefiller/</guid>
      <description>On the Edge of Chaos
Chaos emerges spontaneously in even the simplest systems, and when it does, it renders those systems impossible to predict. What conditions must exist for chaos to arise? How does chaos differ from randomness? How does chaos relate to complexity? We&amp;rsquo;ll ponder these questions and describe how they relate to the interactive installations we build. In particular, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the fascinating boundary between order and chaos — an element we find ourselves returning to again and again in our work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monica Dinculescu</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/monica-dinculescu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/monica-dinculescu/</guid>
      <description>Why you should build silly things
People make things. You make things. Most of the time you make Very Serious Things™️ that help your bosses sell more shoes or saxophones or those tiny coffee packets. And that’s good, because you gotta eat and stuff. But something else has gotta eat, too: your brain. Music is creation, art is creation, code is creation. I think it’s important to goof around with code sometimes, or make things that let other people goof around with code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marque Cornblatt</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/marquecornblatt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/marquecornblatt/</guid>
      <description>A Future Sports Manifesto
Games, play and sport have been around since the dawn of humans and have always been a reflection of time, place and culture. Future Sports are rooted in digital, virtual and immersive technologies, and connect with audiences on new, interactive platforms unimaginable just a few years ago. What defines a future sport and what does it say about our current culture?
Marque has created award-winning art and media for years, earning millions of social media followers and viewers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/blank3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
