<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Performers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</title>
    <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Performers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aaassembly.org/performers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Algobabez</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/algobabez/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/algobabez/</guid>
      <description>ALGOBABEZ have been blasting eardrums with noisy synth-driven algo-pop since 2016. Formed of algorave regulars Shelly Knotts and Joanne Armitage, they use SuperCollider to code and control patterns of weird, wonky, noisy, thumping, danceable music. OK apart, but better together: 2 babes, 2 laptops and 1 sound.
Shelly Knotts is a data musician currently based in Newcastle, UK. She performs live-coded and network music internationally, collaborating with computers and other humans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark Fell</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/markfell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/markfell/</guid>
      <description>Mark Fell is a Rotherham based electronic musician, multidisciplinary artist and producer whose work has persistently challenged the boundaries between dance music and academic computer music practices. Having studied experimental film and video at Sheffield’s notorious Psalter Lane art school at the onset of the city’s techno era (circa 1990), Fell’s approach is equally grounded in the theory and practice of experimental film, radical philosophy and the electronic music subcultures surrounding house and techno.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kit Clayton</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/kit-clayton/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/kit-clayton/</guid>
      <description>Joshua Kit Clayton, better know by his stage name Kit Clayton, is a San Francisco-based electronic and digital musician and computer programmer. In addition to his musical work, Joshua is a programmer for Cycling &amp;lsquo;74, where he is responsible for further development of the Max/MSP MIDI/audio programming environment. He is a significant contributor to Jitter as well, a multi-dimensional data set processing and visualizing architecture with applications in audio, video, and 3d graphics, which is part of the multimedia package Max.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shatter Pattern</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/shatter-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/shatter-pattern/</guid>
      <description>Based on observations of disparate corners of world-phenomena like leaf venation to discarded car parts, Shatter Pattern performs the sonic use and misuse of pattern, the formation of and deformation of ordered structures. By creating rhythmic intricacies and then unexpectedly breaking them down into dysfunctional minutia, Shatter Pattern sonically and visually extrudes worlds from signal interferences that interlope with your perception of reality and being, to reuse the shards of fragmented particles of sound as a vaporous reminder of the primacy of earth&amp;rsquo;s grounding power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>W00dy</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/w00dy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/w00dy/</guid>
      <description>W00dy from Pittsburgh is attempting to bring absurdity to the dance floor with fast bpm&amp;rsquo;s, high energy polyrhythms, and wacky samples. She sees the dance floor as a place for healing, and therefore writes music inspired by moments of catharsis. With two experimental pop records under her belt, RNBW (2015, self released) and Timberdoodle (2016, Fire Talk Records), she moved in a drastically different direction last year with her first dance music record, this world has rendered me (2017, self released).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Selves</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/digital-selves/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/digital-selves/</guid>
      <description>Digital selves is a London based musician who uses live coded algorithms of computer synthesis and found sounds to create a fusion of melodic lo-fi and industrial techno and explores the realm in-between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindohm</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/kindohm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/kindohm/</guid>
      <description>Kindohm is Mike Hodnick, a programmer and sound artist from Chaska, Minnesota, USA. He has performed his brand of coded, algorithmic electronic music internationally, appearing at Algoraves and the International Conference on Live Coding in 2015 and 2016. In 2014, he received the Minnesota Emerging Composer Award from the American Composers Forum. Hodnick sequences sharp synthesis and drums with stacks of TidalCycles pattern code, resulting in bruisingly complex and alluringly minimal live arrangements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vou</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/vou/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/vou/</guid>
      <description>Vou is a digital instrument maker and programmer based in the UK. He utilises a live-coding tracker to generate rhythmic patterns with drawing sounds from electro and braindance. The soundscapes that seek hypnotic states, patterns generated by functions and some rhythmic some of the codified tracks, being split up and re-constructed live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sebastian Camens</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/sebastian-camens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/sebastian-camens/</guid>
      <description>Sebastian Camens is a Dutch/Australian artist and designer based in Seattle. His sound leans into an oxymoronic minimal maximalism, utilising stochastic processes to construct brutal patterns of sound, inflating into the entire frequency range. Camens’ work often transforms sound into near-tangible objects, with implied physical properties of weight and texture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wobbly</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/wobbly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/wobbly/</guid>
      <description>WOBBLY / Jon Leidecker has been producing music under the name Wobbly since 1990, improvising with recordings to produce music which inherently resists the act of being captured. Recent performances deploy a battery of mobile devices driven by their built-in microphones, reacting instantly with error-prone variations on the notes and sounds they believe they are hearing: a tightly-knit orchestra with inhuman reflexes, resulting in structures which the human performer influences more than controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renick Bell</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/renick-bell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/renick-bell/</guid>
      <description>Renick Bell is a computer musician, programmer, and teacher living in Tokyo, Japan. He is a graduate of the doctoral program at Tama Art University in Tokyo, Japan. His current research interests are live coding, improvisation, and algorithmic composition using open source software. He is the author of Conductive, a library for live coding in the Haskell programming language. Previously, he was a doctoral student at Tokyo Denki University. He has a masters degree in music technology from Indiana University and an interdisciplinary bachelors degree in electronic music, studio art, and philosophy from Texas Tech University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TVO</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/tvo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/tvo/</guid>
      <description>TVO is Ruaridh Law; a sound artist and musician based in Paisley, Scotland.
Over 20 years he has performed in groups, in collaborations and solo across a wide range of festivals, arts spaces, venues and clubs as performer, improviser, DJ and artist. Latterly his interests have been in sound art, especially involving psychogeography and esoteric interests. He has been comissioned for new work from organisations such as FutureEverything in Manchester, Unconscious Archives in London, FIBER and Incubate in Amsterdam and the Anthony Burgess Foundation for their William Burroughs at 100 event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charlie Roberts</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/charlie-roberts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/charlie-roberts/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Roberts is an Assistant Professor of Computer Science at Worcester Polytechnic Institute, with an affiliation in the Interactive Media &amp;amp; Game Development program.
His research examines human-centered computing in digital arts practice. He designed and developed a creative coding environment for the browser, Gibber, that he uses both for educational research and audiovisual performances. Gibber is used to teach computational media to middle school, high school and university students in locations around the world, and he has performed with it throughout the US, UK and Asia in the experimental performance genre known as live coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/spatial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/spatial/</guid>
      <description>Spatial is an electronic musician and multimedia artist from London whose work pushes the dynamics of sound system culture incorporating low frequency vibration, hacked code, and optisonic experiments. An unconventional artist in the turbulent realm of bass music, Spatial combines a preoccupation with emergent behaviour, rule based repetition and chaotic systems with an ability to shape dubbed out, cracked and reductive sonics into audible geometric form. Through textured intricate production, Spatial’s releases and live sets bring corporeal presence carved out with a minimalist’s scalpel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spednar</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/spednar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/spednar/</guid>
      <description>a horrid fusion of musique concrete and malfunctioning enterprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>William Fields</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/performers/william-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/performers/william-fields/</guid>
      <description>William Fields (b.1977) is an artist, musician, and composer from the greater Philadelphia area whose work explores algorithmic composition and audio-visual correspondence in the context of real-time improvisational live performance. His music has been released on labels such as Conditional, New York Haunted, Audiobulb, and NOREMIXES. Fields is the host of the algorithmic music radio show FieldsOS on Resonance EXTRA. He has performed live throughout the mid-Atlantic region and Canada. His work was selected and choreographed for dance as part of the International Computer Music Conference (ICMC).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>