<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</title>
    <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on Algorithmic Art Assembly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aaassembly.org/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Windy Chien</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/windy-chien/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/windy-chien/</guid>
      <description>Windy Chien makes art that activates space and elevates the vernacular. She is best known for her 2016 work, The Year of Knots, in which she learned a new knot every day for a year. Her work ranges in size from a knot that can fit in the palm of a child&amp;rsquo;s hand to majestic, room-sized installations that are sought after by private collectors. Following long careers at Apple and in the music industry, she launched her studio in 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elizabeth Wilson</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/elizabeth-wilson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/elizabeth-wilson/</guid>
      <description>Digital selves is a London based musician who uses live coded algorithms of computer synthesis and found sounds to create a fusion of melodic lo-fi and industrial techno and explores the realm in-between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Olivia Jack</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/olivia-jack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/olivia-jack/</guid>
      <description>coder + cartographer who likes to collaborate =)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yotam Mann &amp; Sarah Rothberg</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/yotam-mann-sarah-rothberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/yotam-mann-sarah-rothberg/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Rothberg is an artist who captures the interplay between technology, systems, and the personal, creating meaning through unique and strange interactions. Her idiosyncratic experiences suggest other ways of remembering, thinking, understanding, and communicating. Sarah&amp;rsquo;s work has been exhibited internationally at venues including Sotheby&amp;rsquo;s s2 gallery, MUTEK festival, Mana Contemporary, and bitforms gallery. She teaches virtual reality at NYU (Tisch) and the New School (Lang).
Yotam is a musician and programmer who makes open-source instruments, musical toys and interactive songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M Eifler</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/m-eiffler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/m-eiffler/</guid>
      <description>M Eifler is an artist and researcher at Microsoft spelunking a galaxy of queer bodies, disabled glamor, and compu spaces. Talk: What I&amp;rsquo;ve learned doing gurilla techo- performance at SFMOMA and beyond</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia Litman Cleper</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/julia-litman-cleper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/julia-litman-cleper/</guid>
      <description>Gleaning inspiration from disparate corners of world-phenomena like leaf venation to discarded car parts, Shatter Pattern performs the sonic use and misuse of pattern, the formation of and deformation of ordered structures. By creating rhythmic intricacies and then unexpectedly breaking them down into dysfunctional minutia, Shatter Pattern performances extrude worlds from signal interferences that interlope with your perception of reality and being, to reuse the shards of fragmented particles of sound as a vaporous reminder of the primacy of earth&amp;rsquo;s grounding power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jon Leidecker</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jon-leidecker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/jon-leidecker/</guid>
      <description>Jon Leidecker has been engaged with the medium of electronic music since the mid 1980&amp;rsquo;s, with an emphasis on live performance and collaboration. Early works utilized sonic collage &amp;amp; musical appropriation, growing out of a series of appearances on Negativland&amp;rsquo;s live-mix radio program Over The Edge &amp;ndash; improvising with recorded sounds to produce music which inherently resists the act of being recorded. Recent work investigates the history and musical aesthetics implied by the physics of acoustic and electrical feedback, research into the technology and creative workflow required for immersive sound diffusion (including five years of work as a member of the engineering team for Dolby&amp;rsquo;s 3D sound format Atmos), and the use of mobile devices and their built-in microphones as cybernetic improvising partners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Roberts</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-roberts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-roberts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graham Wakefield</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/graham-wakefield/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/graham-wakefield/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Florin</title>
      <link>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-florin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 15:12:19 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aaassembly.org/speakers/adam-florin/</guid>
      <description>Adam Florin is an independent UX Engineer, who has been creating interactive media for 10+ years for clients such as Levi&amp;rsquo;s®, Facebook, MoMA, General Electric, and Google, earning a South by Southwest Interactive award. He holds an MFA from CalArts, recently participated in the Gray Area incubator, and created the generative music sequencer Patter for Ableton Live.
Adam lives and works in Oakland, CA.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>